Second,
so the main goal of this meeting is to
get feedback on the RFA checklist
workflow that we have.
And kind of like, you know, fine tune it,
go over all the details and get it
working so that it goes to the point
where it's something you guys can use
regularly.
All right,
so I'm just going to go over to the
screen where,
so currently we have it basically divvied
up into a few main sections.
And obviously in the beginning,
it's just a metadata, like, you know,
sponsor, RFA, like the number,
and then program code, opportunity number.
and anything else that you might want
from that RFA document itself. And also,
Tami,
feel free to stop me at any point if you
like look at something or like think of
something as well.
And so the first main section is dates
and deadline. And then also,
as you can see,
there's a section for any notes,
like if there's any special things saying
like any notes for each of the dates.
And then we also had,
we divvied up eligibility into two
criterias,
eligible institutions and then eligible
individuals.
So like any kind of specific individual
eligibility criteria that might come by.
So I can I just ask one question about
the dates? This isn't like a must-have,
Yeah.
but sometimes it's nice.
Some solicitations will say.
Like the next due date is like the 2nd
Tuesday in September or the 4th,
you know what I mean?
They don't give a specific date,
they just say.
Ohh, I see.
Like, you know what I mean? Like,
this isn't always the case,
but it's common with the National Science
Foundation. Like,
Mhm.
what they do is they open the
solicitation and they use it for a while.
So they'll just say, well,
the next time it's due will be the next,
you know, it's reoccurring.
So the next time it's due is the 4th
Tuesday in September from now until.
you know, 2027.
So what I'm just saying is sometimes it's
Okay.
useful to us.
If it could actually tell us that date,
if that's too hard to do,
I want you to try and do it.
Do you know what I mean? Like,
Oh, that's totally doable. Yeah. Yeah.
like if it says something like that,
it'd be nice if it could say, well,
that date is going to be...
And then, yeah,
and then in the notes section for those
You know this.
dates that are calculated,
I could also have it say like this date
was, you know,
like they said the 2nd Tuesday from 2037
or something. And yeah, okay.
That's good to know.
And then anything for
eligibility, like also this,
we want to also like make the workflow so
that it also doesn't have useless
information.
And the other thing when we had the other
version of this, the FOA checklist maker,
which is basically the same thing as this,
but we're going to discontinue that
because that's more.
geared towards PIs because it talks about
merit review criteria and all that.
And is any of that useful for you guys?
Should we include that in here?
I would say not so much like the merit
review stuff.
We're more focused on like what you're
saying, just the eligibility, you know,
how does the, you know,
institutional eligibility,
the PI eligibility,
and then if there's any other, you know,
eligibility restrictions or whatever they
are.
Okay.
And then for award information,
we just have these four criterias that
we're looking at,
but is there anything else you would want
in there? Like later on,
we do have like a budget requirements
section,
which goes down into like indirect cost
rates and all that.
But aside from award integration,
amount per word, number of words,
and then a word date.
Is there anything else we should include
in here?
I am not thinking of anything at this
moment.
Okay, no worries.
And then after this meeting,
I'll also send you a copy of this output
along with the RFA that I used for it,
so that you can also like, you know,
if you think of something later,
you can always, Teams call me, e-mail me,
anything.
All right,
so then we have application components
and we split it up into required
components and then optional components.
Yeah.
Can I, sorry, I was just like,
I kind of generated a detail. I had,
Yeah.
I went through copilot and had it kind of
give me a list of these different
sections and some ideas.
And one thing I don't know if we're
Uh-huh.
covering like an eligibility.
Like if it's like a limited submission
type thing,
Yeah.
does it cover that information?
If it is a limited submission,
would it tell us?
Okay, I will include that.
And would you want that in the
eligibility section, I'm assuming?
Yes.
So like, um, I can, I mean,
I can send you this list,
but it's pretty good just like.
Yeah.
You know,
if there's like citizenship requirements
or early career investigator limited,
you know, sometimes it says like,
you know,
it's only limited to if you're early
career, you know,
investigator or it's a limited submission
Mhm.
to either, you know,
the institution or the faculty member,
like they can only submit so many or we
can only submit so many.
Yeah.
Or if there's some kind of required
you know,
certification or credential they have to
have. Sometimes that does happen.
Can I, can I ask, sorry, I'm joining late,
but do you have an example,
a recent example of any of those types of
things,
like solicitations where that happened?
Oh.
Well,
we have some upcoming proposals like the
NIH or first that are limited to like
early career investigators.
Mm-hmm.
Perfect.
No limited submissions,
I'd have to find an example,
but those do occur.
I got one right in front of me right now
that I'm gonna test.
Yeah, I was going to say,
we've seen quite a few of those.
Yeah, I'm going to test. So anyway,
didn't mean to interrupt,
but I'm going to...
No, yeah, I mean,
it's just it's just always nice for us to
have a heads up when that when those
things happen, so we're aware.
Yeah, we will definitely add that in.
And Barrie, yeah.
I mean, I can...
No, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
Like, I just,
Yeah.
I ran a quick list this morning and it
did give me a pretty good list of some of
the things we might want it to be
checking for and I can send you that.
Yeah, that would be great.
Mm.
All right,
so application components and even in
application components,
are there any more like little subtle
things like that we should be adding in
into like the workflow itself so it
explicitly looks for that in case it's
there and it's ambiguous and it catches
it.
Or even, are there any? Yeah.
So, are these are these all the required?
Sorry,
when I'm are these all the recorded
documents that it's looking for?
Yeah, no, no, no, no worries, go.
Yeah.
And then also, what I was about to ask is,
are there also like for RFAs, NOFOs,
are there any agency specific, you know,
like you mentioned with the dates,
like how NSF does that?
Are there any more things like that we
should be looking for like agency
specific stuff?
Well,
I did have one question and I don't want
to like...
Make this very hard,
but and I tested it this morning and I
What about him?
have a question for you and Barrie how
this works.
So, unfortunately, a lot of the...
the five what we call federal agencies
when they do their solicitations.
They don't include all of the required
components in their announcement because
some of them are standardized.
Does that make sense? So, you know,
they'll some of them are in there,
but not all of them.
Then this is kind of alluding to a
different thing,
but I don't know if there's a way.
I tested it and it kind of worked,
but I wasn't sure what.
The vandalizer was doing if we give it.
If we give it like the...
The RFP or the, you know, the NOFO,
whatever it is, the required document,
and then we give it another document
specific to each.
federal sponsor of what we know are the
standard required documents for each
solicitation,
and then check both of those at the same
time and ask it to run, what does it do?
So you can, like,
you can select multiple documents, like,
you know,
unless the only time I would say that
would be an issue is if one of the
documents is, let's say,
over like 200 pages or something like
that, like, you know, the PAPPG.
Right, yeah. Well,
I wouldn't feed it that.
I'm just saying like,
I just gave it a very short standardized
list. You know,
like here's the 10 required things that
it always asks for.
Yeah.
But I didn't know if it's looking at them
simultaneously or if it's...
So...
I guess what I'm trying to say is what is
going to be the workaround.
And.
To try and get, you know,
the standard required documents that
won't be listed in most.
Solicitations.
So that is totally doable.
I'm assuming that the agents or the
sponsors that this applies to, NSF, NIH,
obviously, they have, right?
Are there others that have like that
standard?
Say that standard backbone.
Well, NIH and Sr. for the...
most relevant ones.
It also applies to Department of Energy
Yeah.
is somewhat standardized and then like
USDA, NIFA.
Okay.
OK.
And then NASA is a little bit harder,
but there is.
somewhat of a generalized list, but like,
again,
NASA is a little bit harder because they
have different kinds of stations.
But anyway, I mean,
I can show you an example.
I didn't want to like, sorry,
like derail this whole thing, but
Oh no, no, this is exactly what we want.
No,
this is this is literally why we're doing
this. It's...
So I tried it right before the meeting,
like I tried it with like just a general
National Science Foundation list and then
I fed it, you know, like a...
just a standardized list and I told it to
do both and it looked like it was working,
but I wasn't quite sure.
I hadn't had time to like really look at
what the output, you know what I mean,
to see what it gave me.
Yeah.
Like if that's going to be the answer.
Oh.
But yeah,
as far as like this table that it's
producing is really good, you know,
as far as like, this is what we want,
as much detail as we can get.
For each, you know,
component that is asking us for.
What, what was the input for this one?
Was it that?
The seating solutions one, 2022. Yep.
Right, okay.
Because I just saw a word limit and I'm
like, no way that's this is an NSF.
They never do that. So.
So,
If you have existing,
like a description of those existing
backbones for those sponsors that you
know is true, that you trust.
I would say send it to us.
And for those that you don't have,
we'll create them.
But what you're asking for,
what I'm hearing is you want to be sure
that the component list and its
restrictions
is complete and sometimes it's only
specified in like the PAPPG or whatever
it is and not the RFA,
but that doesn't mean you still need it.
Right.
And then what you would like is if the
RFA imposes changes on a particular
section, extra sections,
you want all of that in one organized
place.
Exactly. Well, I guess,
but what I'm asking you guys is...
Gotcha.
When we do this, is it better to have...
a separate document, you know what I mean,
in our list, do we have two documents?
Like say we're going to run an NSF,
you know, we, you know,
the Pre Award person uploads an NSF,
you know, RFP or whatever announcement,
Hey.
and then
Is there somewhere else you guys have a
standardized list that we select from
somewhere?
Is that what you're getting at or do we
upload?
I...
You know, an approved templated list.
So, I think we...
I guess I just, you know,
we can work out the logistics.
I didn't know what the easiest.
Because we always have to select which.
you know, Sponsored is, right?
I don't think it'd be too hard for you
Mhm.
guys to try and tell it.
Well, I don't know, so...
Because it is quite different,
do you know what I mean,
Yeah.
what they ask for depending on who it is.
So, let me ask you this.
A.
What would you prefer? Like,
so one option, which I don't...
think we're going to have to do,
but is possible,
is to have this workflow be,
here's the one, you know,
this is NSF RFA checklist maker,
this is NIH, this is NASA, this is DOE,
this is USDA, right? And so you just know,
and then we bake that back.
bone into the workflow and you don't have
to worry about it and all that kind of
stuff and you just go, oh,
here's an NSF and you just run it.
But there's sponsor specific.
The other option is to make one workflow
like this exists and.
try to make it so that it properly
accounts for the known.
the known backbone and there's a lot of
technical ways that Labib could do that
on our side, right?
And if they were all equivalently
trustworthy,
like we showed you all the evidence that
either way produced the results that you
needed,
I'm assuming you'd prefer just having one
workflow that does it. Is that correct?
That's correct.
And my hesitation about making the
different, you know,
baking them into different specific
federal.
Sponsored is just because, as of late,
we've seen more change even into.
what they call the standardized template.
You know, I mean,
Yeah.
you've seen it very for like NSF, right?
You know,
Yeah.
they broke out synergistic activities and
like, oh, now that's its own thing.
I mean, it's standardized now,
but you know, what I'm just saying is.
Mhm.
In the near future,
we could see a standardized element
change. So I'd hate to...
You know what I mean? Like, yeah,
our preference would be just to have one
Yeah, yeah.
template.
however we can do it, you know,
whatever is the easiest way to do it.
Yeah.
Even if, you know,
even if preawarduidahoedu needs to select
a couple different lists,
that's not a big deal.
Or even if we need to upload two lists,
as long as we can get it to work,
you know, the way we need it to work,
whatever is logistically easiest for you
Mhm.
guys.
No, no, no, oh, no, no, no, oh,
absolutely not.
It.
The opposite.
Well, whatever issues, Ross,
it'd be great.
Haha.
No way. You, you, you too,
you tell us how you want it to work and
then we go away and prove to you that it
does work that way. There is,
you're not here to adapt to us.
Yeah, well, yeah,
if there's some way you can read like the
first part of it and go, oh,
I recognize this is an NSF solicitation.
We're going to use the, you know,
these elements to make sure it's included.
Yep.
I'm sure that's how it's going to work,
right? Something to that, in fact.
Yeah, yeah,
that's Labib's problem to solve.
You guys aren't here to adapt to our what
we do.
Yeah, we got it cleared.
Right.
Right, well,
that would be nice because I will say we
have a lot of solicitations that are not
also the big, what we call the big 5,
right? I mean,
there are a lot of them that we do run.
We need to run that,
that this is going to work fine for,
right?
We want all these elements in there.
Could you, I mean,
I kind of jumped in on this late,
so I'm not sure if you guys had a
trajectory mapped out already,
but I've got a question.
You can defer it if you like.
But let's say this workflow produces,
like we've proven to you that it produces
reliable results.
that you can trust for this,
the big 5 plus the long tail of different
sponsors. Like,
how do you how do you then use this?
So say you have this report, you know,
like it's four or five pages of like.
Condensed information, then what?
We use it as, you know,
ourselves as Pre Award, you know,
administrators to review it for, you know,
to prepare it to.
you know, review the proposal.
That's the point of it.
So we don't have to read the 200 pages of,
or however many pages there are,
that would be the most useful thing.
And then I don't want to skip ahead
either,
So...
but then the second thing we would like,
which this is going to do,
is just have like a checklist, you know,
like a checklist that...
Maybe we can generate.
a workflow on its own,
like a PI checklist that we can give to
just the faculty member or the, you know,
DGA. Like, okay, we, you know, here's,
because we need this full list, right?
Faculty member doesn't necessarily want
Okay.
all to know all of this, but you know,
it's like we're, I was meeting with them,
okay, here's.
Mhm.
So we want to checklist. So I mean,
those are the ways we would use it.
But specifically,
so let's just use from your perspective,
you've got this high quality checklist of
like,
these are the things that I need to check
before I can, and it's not,
these aren't the only things obviously,
but it's a...
It's a pretty comprehensive list of a lot
of the stuff you have to do.
You got to check all these things.
to make sure that they meet the
requirements prior to submission. Correct?
That's what this is for.
Yes.
But what I want to know is...
Let's say you've got it.
It's trustworthy information.
Then what are you doing?
You have this open on another screen and
then you're in Veris and you're sort of
looking at the various documents.
Like tell me about that part.
Yes, I mean, we would,
I would have this open and I would be
comparing it to...
all the different documents.
So if I'm looking at the project abstract,
I'd be looking at this list going on,
what does the project abstract says?
It says it's got to be 10 font.
It says it can be 3 pages. It said,
you know,
I would rely on whatever this says for
Okay.
each component to know that we may have
all of them and whatever
It specifically saw us.
Yeah, so I would be comparing, yeah,
exactly.
I'd be comparing the side by side with
each.
Big.
Document we need to review.
So.
Ben.
Is it in the right order in terms of?
the order in which you conduct your
review,
like are there ways that formatting and
organization of the information could be
improved so that it more naturally
matches how you proceed through that part?
Um, I'd have to look at that. I mean...
OK.
I think so far, I mean, overall,
are you just talking the component part
or the whole thing?
Just from like from the beginning to the
end.
Like the whole, yeah, the whole thing.
The whole thing, yeah.
I think right now it's in pretty good
order. I mean, that's, I mean,
we want to know at the beginning,
what are the due dates? Are we, you know,
Mm-hmm.
the eligibility?
That's the first thing we're always
Mhm.
looking at. You know,
what is the award information? And then,
you know,
what are the documents or budget
limitations?
Okay, so budget.
And then.
Right now is near the bottom,
so would you say that putting budget
after the word information would be
better,
like the budget requirements and policies?
Yeah, that would probably be better.
And then how about submission details?
Should that be also right before the
application components or?
I know it's small changes,
but whatever helps, you know,
like when you're looking at that screen,
what order do you think about it?
Right.
Yeah, I think both of those could go.
Before the documents.
Sierra, you have any?
Like your input too,
you've done a lot of this.
I agree that I would like the budget,
the budget section, like right below,
like the due dates,
because that's probably the next thing
that I look at.
So that I know how long of a process this
should be allocated for.
Could you,
what do you mean process it should be
allocated for in terms of your workload?
Yeah, so like.
If there is.
Depending on the budget requirements,
like if everything is not allowed and
things like that,
that may delay the process and make my
review a longer review.
Ah.
So like our TPS like system,
basically if there's,
if waivers are needed,
I need to start that process way earlier
than I would.
So if I saw this and I was like, oh,
this is a simple review,
I can start this a little bit closer to
the due date.
and not hound the PI versus I need to
start on this a week or two weeks earlier
and make sure that they get their waivers
in and things like that.
That's very interesting, so...
Yeah, so she's right. I mean,
so like if there's cost share.
You know, then with our system,
we're going to need a 10-day review if
they need a waiver. I mean, in this case,
it's, I think this is,
I don't know if this is a federal
solicitation or not. If it is, you know,
Pal.
then we wouldn't need a waiver. Actually,
FFAR is a, I believe, non-profit.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because if it's like federal nonprofit,
But...
then it doesn't make the process longer.
But if it's anything else, it, yeah.
Right.
But right, I mean,
cost share indirect limitations are big,
List.
especially if it's...
Well, when we get into the USDA NIFAs,
they're almost all TFFA,
which require a longer review.
Mhm.
So what other flags?
So cost share and something requiring an
F&A waiver would sort of,
those are flags that say, oh,
this one could take a while.
What are some other ones?
L.
Those are, those are my main ones.
I mean,
those are ones we know from the
And.
solicitation. I mean, you know,
ones we know from faculty or whether
we're going to have subawards,
but you know,
we aren't going to know that from a
solicitation. So, right, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, that's a different thing,
yeah.
Because...
I will say,
and I don't want to jump ahead either,
one thing we do that we would like to
request,
which I don't believe we are doing right
now, and you can correct me if I'm wrong,
is adding in terms and conditions.
Okay.
to looking for those.
like all the terms and conditions we need
to look for.
like indemnification,
I have a list of them,
but there are terms and conditions
preawarduidahoedu needs to look for in
Yeah,
that's a separate workflow that Labib is
all these, right?
cooking up that that looks at RFAs and
award letters, frankly,
for those kinds of things.
So is that something that that list can
be incorporated into this workflow?
Yeah,
we can definitely add in like another
section, maybe at the very top,
like right by the word information that,
you know,
it got flagged for identification or like,
you know, this,
you need to work with North Korea for
this one. It's flagged. So, you know.
Yeah, internet, yeah, yeah.
Right. Well,
like what Sierra is saying is those are
things we also need to know right away
because if there is an indemnification or
certain terms and conditions,
then we need to flag that because then we
need to,
that also takes longer because we need to
work with contract review unit because
then we need to send the proposal to them
Mhm.
right away.
Because they need to review it.
And those are like more general.
Are there any university specific stuff
we look for for any of these sections or
like the information or even even UI
specific budgetary requirements or
policies that we should be aware about?
Well, the terms and conditions are,
you know,
we have a UI specific list and on.
Okay.
Yeah, we've got that well already.
Yeah.
But the thing,
this is really useful because what I'm
hearing is that regardless of whether
it's a workflow for what we've got here
and then a workflow for terms and
conditions, when somebody uploads an RFA,
one of the things that...
like in terms of the information
hierarchy that you all need,
I feel like what you're saying is a
section at the top that that sort of says,
hey,
Here's some stuff that's going to make
this a longer process than usual.
This one requires these waivers.
It requires a letter from the president.
You know,
it's got 16 different contract terms in
it that the state will make us reject,
right?
And then it's followed by more of a
checklist.
Kind of a thing in the order that you
would go through it, but like that,
that initial, like, ohh,
better get on this section, it it.
Yeah, if we could do that, and you know,
you pointed out a really important thing,
Barrie, which we didn't mention yet,
is if it does require like an
institutional letter of commitment,
that's another one, that's a big one,
Yeah.
Okay.
especially if it's, you know,
a presidential or vice provost letter
Yeah.
that is
A sixteen-day.
Yeah.
Oh.
Because, you know, Labib,
the institutional risk workflow that
you're working on for Cindy, actually,
some of those things are in that rubric,
Yeah.
and we could just take them from there
and put them in here.
That's what I was thinking, yeah.
Um...
It, because...
You know, there are triggers that...
Uh, yeah, like Sierra was saying.
It affects like how you, okay,
I got to pick this one up because it's
going to be two weeks of hounding people
for stuff in order to get this submitted.
Yeah, and like you said,
we kind of have to know right away
because sometimes we...
you know,
we are already behind the schedule that
we need to be on and then we have to,
you know, put it on other avenues.
Oh yeah.
So yeah,
it's always right when we get proposals
now, it's like, as soon as we,
that's why this is so important to us,
as soon as we can run it through
something to get the information we need,
then.
you know, then it's like, okay.
Boom, boom, boom, what do we need?
Like what you're saying, Barrie,
that's a great idea. You know, at the top,
if we could have some kind of.
No boxing.
No, car share, institutional letter,
what you know, whatever.
possible.
flags we need, you know.
Could we call it Sierra's Box of Doom?
And it's just a bunch of red flags of
Yeah.
Sure, we could.
It really is the box of dude.
just like the stuff that's going to make
this one suck. I don't know.
Yeah.
It's just like, it's just like,
like the preparedness,
like being extra prepared on how long
it'll take because I have made that
Yeah, yeah.
mistake where I didn't look at the budget
requirements until I was reviewing and
then it was like F&
A waiver and I was like, oh my gosh.
So then that had to be expedited. So
Mhm.
Like,
I think that is the first thing that we
really look at now. And then like,
we do our review after those things have
been retrieved,
then we can go through the checklist and
be like, give me all this stuff.
What?
What proposals are both of you working on
right now? Like, I mean,
Yeah.
I'm assuming you're both, you've both got.
..
I mean, I don't know, Sierra,
like how many do you have right now that
you're working with? Like,
that's a data assigned to you.
Well, I'm an intern,
so I only have one right now,
Perfect.
because the the Pre Award department's
pretty...
But what about you, Tami? How many,
how many are you handling right now?
Well,
it depends on when you say they're due.
I mean,
I'm working on a bunch that aren't due
immediately because we're waiting for
some releases. But I mean,
in any given week,
preawarduidahoedu can be working on 5 to
12 proposals due in that week.
But what I'm looking,
the reason I'm asking is like, Sierra,
could you give us the RFA you're working
with right now?
And then same with you, Tami,
like give us the five RFAs that you that
Yeah.
are on your radar right now that and
we'll start using those as while you're
doing this stuff,
we'll start using those to modify and
refine this workflow.
Because since the context for you right
now is like real, we can just say, hey,
Yeah.
we refined the workflow.
And so now the report looks like this.
And then you'll immediately be able to
see, oh, it missed that or yeah,
Okay.
it's highlighting this.
You know what I'm saying?
And.
Is that bad?
I'm getting the sense you don't want to
do that.
Oh yeah, I can do that. That's no problem.
No, that's fine.
Yeah.
The one I have right now is just a
standard NSF, but...
But there's no just ever, right?
So because you're doing it,
Yeah.
that means if we get this working and we
send you a report and you're in the
context of that,
it's way easier for you and more useful.
to review that information because if you
see stuff that's right,
you see what I'm saying?
I'd rather test with what you're doing
now than some arbitrary RFA from three
years ago.
Right.
It, you know, so if you send us that,
even though it's a standard one,
Yeah.
these things still have to work with
standard ones, you know.
Right,
and some of the other things like in that
Mhm.
box, the beginning barrier would be like,
you know,
does anything require a signature?
Those are things that we always have to
be aware of that sometimes are buried in
these things, you know, AOR signature.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
And then, you know,
can the PI submit in the portal or does
it have to be submitted by, you know,
the institution?
Because that's another thing we run into.
Yep.
Because those also affect what kind of.
Okay.
especially with private foundations.
Tier of support we.
Provide or they select.
Which we can, you know, we, if you want,
Pre Award team can come up with help
develop that list.
A list of problematic.
Well,
like things in the beginning we would
like to see flagged, like...
Yeah.
Cost share.
No signature.
I mean.
We've hit the...
FNA restriction.
Yeah, we've hit the big ones already.
What I don't want you to do is spend any
of your...
time thinking about an additional,
you know, like this kind of stuff.
But if you do remember something, oh wait,
yeah, this is a pain. You should eat.
Well, I've got, yeah, no, I agree.
So we've got some upcoming order called
NIH for first proposals that I'm working
with a faculty member that I need to meet
Yeah.
with her that are, you know, we've,
I am Pre Award already developed a list.
Perfect.
So, you know, if we, I can give you that.
Okay.
solicitation and see what you guys can do
with it because there are institutional
Yep.
letter of commitments,
there are chair dean letters, there are...
Awesome.
Lots of special things in that
solicitation.
So why don't we do those two?
We'll do this NSF sure first and
whichever NSF or NIH sure first, sorry,
and then whichever NSF you're working on
now, Sierra,
we'll add that to our testing portfolio
because it will just make it.
But you know, easier to,
if we go through a refinement phase,
it'll be, one,
it'll be more useful to you guys, and two,
it'll be easier for you to look at it and
go, oh wow, that's great,
it caught everything, or oh,
look at that terrible answer it gave us.
One question I did have when I,
before this meeting,
I was going back and looking at some
things I had done. We had, you weren't,
I don't think involved in these, Barrie,
but there were some what were called
Department of Energy DOE Genesis
proposals.
which were very large solicitations.
And yesterday I couldn't get Vandalizer
to run.
The announcement, like it said,
was too large.
And then today I ran it and it ran. So...
Mhm.
I didn't know if there was some kind of.
Limit.
Could you send me that one as well?
Yes.
Labib and I have experienced a few bugs
yesterday while we were testing all this
stuff as well.
I was getting like truncated results.
Yeah.
So I need to check in with John about
this. I filed a support ticket, but...
Maybe we were having like temporary
context window issues.
That would explain it.
Yeah, I mean, what?
Yeah.
Let them figure all that stuff out, but...
Well, the reason I just ask is,
is there going to be any limitation on
this? Because, you know,
we can get an announcement that,
or a solicitation that is.
you know, 200 pages or more,
I'm hoping we aren't going to have a
limitation issue.
Um...
I'm glad you brought that up because now
that I think about it,
Barrie and I are like with John,
we can actually
you know,
calculate that and actually have an
estimate for you guys of what the limits
are. So that's a good point.
Well, I mean, it's not normal,
but like I think this one was like 150 or
160,
but like Department of Energy is the one
who tends or Department of Defense or...
Yeah.
And I know we need to check on this
because I don't think it's been answered
yet if we can put Department of Defense
information in here yet.
If that's been cleared, but...
I don't know either. So let's assume,
I mean, public RFPs are fine, but.
I have to check back with Eric on that,
but...
Right. Well, anyway,
what I'm trying to say is some of those
Yeah.
solicitations can get rather large and...
Yeah.
It would be nice if we can.
you know,
run them because those are the ones that
are most time consuming for us to go
through.
Yeah, again.
And especially this DOE Genesis thing
that they did,
they came up with different iterations of
it. But anyway, long story short,
they tend to stick things at the end of
it, you know, that are important.
Mhm.
I do.
Yeah.
Ohh.
Funny.
I'm pretty sure, so, but...
I'm pretty sure it's not the first
proposal we've gotten.
That's the STEM K through 12.
Yeah, yeah, so...
That's good.
But yeah, Tami, like the NIH, sure,
and then an example of a big one,
especially if you're working with it
right now, that would be really good.
There are ways we can deal with that,
but we have to figure out what is the
limit in terms of just a straight up
workflow and.
how do we communicate that to the user so
that if you try to run a workflow on
something big like that,
it doesn't just silently fail you by only
looking at the 1st 50 pages, you know?
And then...
Well, I think when I first ran the,
I mean, this was the Genesis,
this was like back in like April or May.
When I first tried to run it,
Yeah.
it would like run for like 40 minutes and
I don't think it ever really did finish.
I think it did truncate it.
Because that was when, you know,
we didn't have the capability yet,
which was fine. But like I said yesterday,
just for some reason, it actually,
it gave me an error, which was nice,
because it just said it was too large or
something to that effect.
Anyway.
Yeah.
But there's ways for us to deal with that.
It's just we want them to be low friction
Yeah.
for you guys, right?
Like we don't want you to have to know,
oh,
I need to upload this as a knowledge base
and then I can, you know, like it's like,
oh God, you got enough to worry about.
Don't. So.
Like for example,
when you upload a document like that and
you try to run the workflow,
I can envision an error message that says,
this is way too big for this workflow.
Would you like to run it through this
alternative knowledge base thing instead?
Click this button and it, and it,
I made a note for you.
you don't like it.
just lets you do it in an alternative way.
Sure. Yeah, we'd say yes. Thank you.
That would be great.
Yeah.
But these things that you guys are
raising, where like...
the edge cases and all of that kind of
stuff.
This is what everybody's struggling with,
right?
And all of these things are these tiny
points of friction that make it so that
you all go this.
This is,
this is this workflow is too much of a
pain in the *** to.
for me to bother with right now.
I got a lot of stuff to do.
I know how to do it. I can't be, you know,
running this workflow and then worrying
that it...
you know,
sometimes doesn't do what it needed to do.
And so that all of those friction points
are things we need to smooth out,
as in me and Labib, not you two.
Sure.
And is there something built into this
and I'm sure there probably is like that
it tells it not to like...
hallucinate anything or make up any...
Yeah.
But, yeah.
But that's why we're doing all these
evaluations so that we can prove to you
Right.
that that it doesn't.
Well, no, that's fine. I just, like, I've,
you know, we've all done it. You know,
So.
Yep.
I've ran things through different AI and,
you know, it'll tell me, well, you know,
NIH project narrative is, you know,
15 pages, which isn't true because it,
Yep.
you know,
just throwing out something which is a
standard NSF and like each.
Yeah.
You know, a sponsor is different. So like,
I'd rather have it not tell me anything
than make something up that's not.
you know, correct.
Yeah.
That's confidently wrong.
Yes, like any of these, you know,
I don't want them to tell me something
Yeah.
that is...
Not correct.
Yeah.
What would it take for both of you?
To.
where you would be convinced that this
works. What do you need to see?
In order to say, yeah, this total,
this is a, this is bulletproof.
I'm going to use it every time.
I guess, I mean, personally,
I would need to like...
read a couple of them myself, you know,
and then read it and see what it,
you know what I mean? Just, I mean, just,
you know, cross-checking it.
Mhm.
And, and...
Early on, I saw,
I don't know if it was early vandalizer
or whatever, but I've seen, you know,
things weren't.
I don't know if it was even vandalizer,
but you know, just...
Yeah, I mean,
just knowing that it's giving the correct
information, because, like, if if I,
you know, we get something wrong,
it's not good, you know, and you know,
proposal can get rejected.
And...
And so what I'm hearing is that you,
we need to find a low-lift way for you to
use this.
and verify the information in the context
of what you're already doing,
which is why I think running these things
on proposals you're actively working on.
would be a good idea because that is when
you're reading,
you're doing it the current way anyway.
And you're, you would, you know,
it's like, okay,
I'm going to pull out the eligibility
stuff and I'm doing that check.
Why don't I have a look at the
eligibility section from the workflow and
just sort of see how they line up?
Right.
Instead of saying, hey,
we ran this on a two-year-old RFA,
can you check to see if it's correct?
That's just not going to be good.
Yeah, no, I totally agree. Honts.
Yeah.
Okay, I feel like we're over time.
Did we get everything you needed, Labib?
Yes.
One last thing,
so in the budget requirements and
policies,
so all the bullet points you see are what
we told this workflow to explicitly look
at, like the big categories.
Just briefly looking it over,
do you think,
are we missing any more of these big
categories in there?
I think they're fine.
Those are definitely all the big ones.
And
Maybe, like...
Yeah,
because the one thing I would be like
also interested in is like personal
effort and sometimes there's restrictions
on personnel and how much they can
allocate and stuff so.
Okay.
Yeah, I don't agree with Sierra.
I don't know if there's...
Maybe this list doesn't have it.
I don't know if it's looking for it,
but like I have a list here,
like any special restrictions,
because sometimes they'll give you a list
of allowable or unallowable.
So we would like want either one of those,
because like sometimes they'll say the PI
is required to travel to one meeting in
Washington, DC. We would want.
Yep.
to know that and like I know that's not
necessarily budget,
Okay.
but it is because we have to allocate
that in the budget and then it'll say
Mhm.
like that is restricted to, you know, $2,
000 a year or whatever or basically any
special budget requirements, whether it's,
you know, incentives, travel.
International, you know, like any.
Yeah.
O.
Any special, you know, allowable,
unallowable. I mean,
it says that I guess right there,
allowable, unallowable,
but there's any other special.
Get so.
I ran the current version on the PCL test
bed one,
You know.
which I know has all sorts of special
stuff.
And then budget requirements and policies,
it says other considerations include
budget for an annual in-person PI meeting
each year covering travel for the PI team
and host site expenses such as venue food
and related costs.
So in this particular case,
it did catch that.
Yeah, that.
Thanks.
Yeah, that's good.
That's exactly what we'd want to know.
So we're aware that we need,
that needs to be included.
So yeah,
I did probably is looking for that stuff.
We just, it's just not in this.
Yeah.
And yeah, we'll make sure the workflow,
like even though it is catching it in
Ohh.
this one case, like Barry said,
but we'll make sure that it's explicitly
mentioned in the prompt to also look for
those things.
Yeah, and I'm like, I mean,
there's a list here,
but I'm sure it's looking for, you know,
if there's any salary cap,
salary limitations, you know,
like tuition,
if tuition is or isn't allowed.
Sometimes they'll say no tuition is
allowed.
Mhm.
Sometimes they'll say we don't allow
equipment.
Mhm.
or they'll say you can only spend.
$5,000 on equipment or $10,
000 equipment cap or something.
I don't know. But anyway.
Or if it's an MRI, it'll say,
you're only allowed to spend money on
Yeah, that's another one too. Yeah,
you can only,
equipment or, you know.
this budget is only for equipment,
no salaries.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, whatever it is,
if there's anything that's special we
want to know, like us,
which is hopefully going to come out in
Mhm.
the other considerations.
Does this elevate to the level in the
information hierarchy of that stuff at
the top that makes it a bigger lift in
terms of review and approval?
Or is it just got to make sure we cover
this, but it's just a part of a checklist?
Usually that stuff is more just a part of
the checklist because the PI should know
those things when they're creating their
budget.
So unless it limits F&A or required,
like there's some budgetary things we've
already discussed that get it up into
that red flag box,
but having to go to a meeting or budget
for this is not, not bad. Yeah.
Yeah.
Right, yeah, no, correct. That one effect.
Yeah.
Just, just a need to know for awesome.
Mhm.
Okay, I,
I gotta jump because I need to try to get
to campus now that my Home Depot lumber
and concrete has arrived, so...
Alright, well,
thank you so much for taking this time.
Ohh.
This really helps us help you in the
future, very soon.
Yeah.
Yeah, we appreciate it.
Bye.
Thank you.
See you guys.
Bye.